Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create a main menu for our two D game.
To get started, go to the Widget Blueprint folder and right click and go User Interface Widget Blueprint.
Bullets widget our main menu underscore widget blueprint.
Then if we open this up.
And on the palette, look for a canvas panel.
Drag this canvas panel into the designer.
Then look for some text.
And drag it to the center of our screen.
Make sure we anchor it to the center of our screen.
And just make this text whatever you want to call the game.
So I'm going to call this my 2D action platformer game.
Let's increase the size of our text.
So if I go to font and go over to size, I'll make this 100.
And let's just expand this box to bits around our text.
Next, we're going to create some menu items.
So we're going to create a start button.
And when we click this button, it's going to open up all the levels that we have in our game.
And we'll also create a quit button so we can quit our main menu and exit this game.
If we go to palette and look for a vertical box.
This and place this beneath our text.
And make sure to also anchor this to the bottom left of the screen.
Then in the product, look for a button.
Track two of these into the vertical box.
Next, look for some text and track two pieces of text on top of the buttons.
Make this first taxi start.
And make the second text say quit.
Then if we set the first one, I'm just going to go through padding and add a padding of 50.
Just so that there's a bit of a gap between our buttons.
Then I'm going to select both buttons and increase the size of the text a bit.
So I'll make it 40.
And we just move this down a bit.
The next thing we're going to do is make it so that when we click the start button, it's going to show
us all the levels that we have inside of our game.
If we go to the palette and look for our horizontal box.
Track this into the center of our canvas panel and then look for a button and drag this button inside
the horizontal box.
Then look for some text and drag this text inside of the button.
Just select this text and let's make it say level one.
So they go to content and then I'm going to type in level one.
We're going to make it so that when we click on this button, it will take us to level one.
Let's also make sure to just anchor this to the middle of our screen.
Then if we go to search, look for visible and by default we're going to make this hidden in game and
we'll make it so that when we click the stop on, we'll make this box visible.
One last thing.
Just select this box and check this is variable one and just call this level box.
Then go back to the palette and look for a button.
Track it in and place it on the bottom right corner of our screen.
Then look for some text.
I track this text inside of the button.
Then just make this text say go back.
So if I go to my content, I'll make you say go.
Back and make sure this is available and pull this off the back button.
And also make sure that the visibility is hidden by default.
So look for visibility and just make sure this is hidden.
And then finally, let's make sure to anchor this to the bottom right corner of our screen.
That way, when we show this HUD on our screen, the button will be there.
Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is add some functionality to our buttons.
If we just select this box, check this is variable one and rename this main menu box.
Okay.
So the first bond we're going to give functionality is the start button.
If you select it, scroll down and go on clicked.
When we click on this button, we're going to drag in our go back button and our level box, and we're
going to make it so that we can see these buttons.
So if we just drag off here and look for set visibility and make sure that this is set to visible and
just connect the go back button to Target, when we click on this button, we're going to make it so
that we can see both of these elements.
After we do this, we're going to drag in our main menu box and we'll make it so that we can't see this.
So if we drag up here and look for set visibility and under visible change, this to be hidden and then
connect this node.
The next button will set up is going to be the quick button.
If we select it, scroll down and go on clicked.
When we click, this button will quit our game and close it.
To do that, just drag up here and look for the quick game note.
This will automatically make our game close and quit.
Next, let's set up our level one.
If we select it and scroll down and go on clicked.
When we click on this button, we're going to open up our main level.
So if we drag up here and look for open level by name and type in the name of your level.
So I name mine level one.
So here I'm going to type in level one.
Make sure it's spelt correctly, otherwise it won't work.
Then if we go to our go back button, scroll down and go on clicked.
When we click the go back button.
We're going to do the opposite of what we do here.
So I'm going to copy all these notes.
And pace them here.
So this time we're going to make it through the go back button and the level box are no longer visible.
So set them to be hidden and then we'll make it so that we can see the main menu box.
So change this to be visible and then go to the designer and we can click, compile and save.
Okay.
With this we have created our main menu.
The next thing we need to do is make it so our main menu can appear in a level.